Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut (1910-2003) 1738-2006 AR 25309 / MF 932
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series I: W. Gunther Plaut Genealogy, 1738-2005; 7.875 linear feet.
  - Subseries 2: Other Research Files, 1860-2006; 1.25 linear feet.
    - A) Correspondence
      - Correspondence and Notes - Other Plauts, 1936, 1973-1998 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Other Plauts - Lowenstein, Steven (LBI), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Other Plauts - Plaut, Walter H., 1960-1981 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Various Plauts, 1937-1944, 1973-2001 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Eisendrath Family Members, 1969-1979 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - Elwood, Kyle, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Falk, Julian, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - Flamm Family Members - Correspondence and Notes, 1977-1991 (Box 6, Folder 74)
      - Franklin, Karen, 1982-1997 (Box 6, Folder 75)
      - General E-mail, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Germany, 1973-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Hessisches Hauptstaatsarchiv 1973-1987
        Standesamt Idar-Oberstein 1973
        Standesbeamte in Walldorf 1973
        Standesamte Dortmund 1973
        Katholische Kirchengemeinde St. Peter 1974
        State Archives Falkenberg 1973
      - Gold, David (Haifa), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Goldsmith, Charlotte and Bernard, 1977-1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Goldsmith Family, 1977-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Hassan, Jacob - Plaut Name Research, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Hertzmann, Walter - Descendants of Hertz Schoenholz, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Inquiries, 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Inquiries - Paris, 1977-1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Jewish Historical Society of New Haven, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Johnson, Edward I. - Research, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Klein, Jack - Blout Family (Washington, D.C.), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Leo Baeck Institute, 1975-1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Mainzer Family, 1973-1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
        Manizer, Omri
        Mainzer, Yehudah
      - Mainzer Family - Correspondence and Notes, 1974-1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Mayer, Henry, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Ogushwitz, Gertrude S., 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Plaut, Abraham L. - Family - Correspondence and Family Trees, 1977-1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Plaut, Daniel, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Plaut, Evelyn, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Plaut, Evelyn - Elizabeth to Evelyn Plaut, 1973-1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Plaut, Evelyn - Evelyn to Elizabeth Plaut, 1973-1989 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Plaut/ Fink - Correspondence and Notes, 1973-1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
        Arnold, Mary 1988
        Everell, Hilda 1987
        Fefferman, Laverne 1988
        Fink, Renato and Ester 1991
        Fitzmaurice, Marcia 1996
        Juedische Kultusgemeinde Gross-Dortmund 1973-1974
        Melzer, Joan G. 1999
        Plaut, Daniel 1996
        [Plaut?], Ida 1980-1981
        Plaut, Joshua 1988
        Plaut, Sidney 1990
        Plaut, Tom 1996
        Saltzman, Murray 1992
        Standesamt Dortmund-Dorstfeld 1973-1974
        Wertheimer, Herbert 1994
        Wise, Martha 1985
        Unidentified
      - Plaut, Joshua - Correspondence and Clippings, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Plauth Sr., William, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Publishing, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Queries, 1926-1938, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Rakow, L. (England), 1982-1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Rottenberg, Dan, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Russian Plauts, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Sack, Sallyann - Avotaynu Journal, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Sobel, Henry I. (Brazil), 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Spencer, Alan - Search Magazine, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Various Plauts, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 34)
        Franklin, Karen 1999
        Gumprich, Michelle 1999
        Plaut, Carmi 1999
        Wachtel, Alan 1998
      - Wasserman, Henry, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - World Book of Plauts, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - B) Notes, Family Trees, and Collected Documentation
      - Aufbau Clippings - Names, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Australia and New Zealand - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Blout/ Plaut Trees (Fargo/ Washington/ Boston), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Books - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Books and Records Read, 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Cincinnati - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Cities - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Dutch Sources, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Ems Family Tree, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Family Photographs, 1908-1997 (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Family Photographs - Germany, 1910-1930s, 1986-1993 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Family Trees - Charles Frederick Plaut Branch, 1973, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Family Trees and Notes - Various Plauts, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - Fink, Ester (Plaut) - Nutrition Article, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - General Research - Notes, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Hessen - Reference Books, 1974-1986 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - Israel Data, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Jerusalem and Frankfurt am Main - Notes, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Kentucky Plauts, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Leipziger Messgaeste - Notes, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Louisiana - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Mannheim Family Members, 1973-1995 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Mormons - Records, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Names - German from Hebrew, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - New York Times Articles - Notes, 1974-1982 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - Norwich (CT) Plauts - Photographs and Clippings, 1905, 1968, 1982-1990 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Ornstein Memoirs, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 63)
      - Other Data and Records - Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - Peking, 1940-1996 (Box 7, Folder 65)
      - Plat, Joseph ibn - Research, undated, 1962, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 66)
      - Plaut Biographies, 1992-2004 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      - Plaut, Feiwel (Philipp) - Juedisches Gemeindeleben in Kolin, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 68)
      - Plaut, Jonathan - Clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 69)
      - Plaut, Joseph - Clippings, undated, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 70)
      - Plaut, Joshua - Biographical Articles - Clippings, 1984-1997 (Box 7, Folder 71)
      - Plaut, L.M. - Documentation from American Jewish Archives, 1860-1861 (Box 7, Folder 72)
      - Plaut, Leo and Fanny - Notes, 1973-1983 (Box 7, Folder 73)
      - Plaut, W. Gunther - Clippings, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 74)
      - Plauts - Directories, 1968-1978 (Box 7, Folder 75)
      - Plauts in Germany - Notes, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 76)
      - Plauts in the 1500s and 1600s - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
      - Plauts in the 1700s - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
      - Plauts in the 1800s - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - Unidentified Plauts, 1981-1988 (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Washington, D.C. - Notes, undated, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - C) Unsorted
      - Additional Plauts - Notes, 1914, 1973-1986 (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Correspondence, 1992-1999 (Box 7, Folder 83)
        Baird, Carol 1992
        Dannenberg, 1993, 1998
        Wormser, Alan J. 1991
        Plaut, Carlos 1994
        Plaut, Erich Kurt 1995
        Plaut, S. Michael 1996
      - Correspondence - E-mail, 1997, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - Correspondence - Personal, 1986-1995 (Box 7, Folder 85)
      - Correspondence - Personal, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 86)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family Members, 1973-2005 (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family Members - Baird, Carol Davidson, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family Members - Friend Family Members, 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family Members - Remembrances of Selma Gumprich Plaut, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Correspondence - Plaut Family Members - Stewart, Ruth, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Loose Papers, 1990-1997 (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - Correspondence and Notes - To Be Filed, 1980s? (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - Correspondence and Notes - To Be Filed - Frank, Helene - Buxbaum Family, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - Documentation and Clippings, undated, 1894, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Notes, 1970-1980s? (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Notes, 1984?-1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Notes - Juden in Eschwege, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Notes - Records, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Plaut Research - Various, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Plaut Research - Various - Loose Papers, undated, 1990?-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: Gumprich and Rosenthal Families, 1858-1999; 1 linear foot.
    Divided by family.
    Subseries 3 is comprised of files originally located together and labeled as pertaining to the Gumprich and Rosenthal families. These families appear to have been related to one another, and were connected to the Plaut family via W. Gunther Plaut's mother, Selma Gumprich Plaut. Folder titles were derived from those originally given by Elizabeth Strauss Plaut; folders were arranged alphabetically during processing.
    This subseries primarily holds correspondence on the genealogy of the Gumprich and Rosenthal families as well as family trees and some notes. Much of the correspondence also includes personal details about family members. Some drafts, notes, receipts, and correspondence relating to the publishing of Elizabeth Plaut's book,The Gumprichs of Münster/ Westphalia: a Tale of Four Continents will also be found among the papers here. Information on the Rosenthal porcelain company is also available in this subseries.
    - A) Gumprich
      - Alberts Family - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - American Jewish Archives Research, undated, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Borghorst Research, undated, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Borghorst/ Trier Data, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Brighton (England) Hostel - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Brighton (England) Hostel - Correspondence and Memoir Excerpts, 1992-1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Brown, Lotte - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Carmi, Chaim and Gad - Correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Unsorted, 1918-1939, 1987-1999 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence and Research - Unsorted, undated, 1985-1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Dessauer Data - Correspondence, 1981-1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Emigration from Wuerttemberg - Correspondence with Government Agencies, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Family Tree Data - Salomon Gumprich and Sophie Meyerberg's Descendants - Correspondence and Research, 1973-1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Family Tree, 1980s? (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Family Trees, 1980s-1990s? (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Family Trees, 1990s? (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Family Trees and Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Gumprich, Albert - Branch - Correspondence, 1973-1992 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Gumprich, Amshel? - Correspondence, 1973-1983 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Gumprich, David - Family Trees, 1973-1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Gumprich Family (Australia) - Correspondence and Notes, 1976-1982 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Gumprich, Gustave - Branch - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Gumprich, Gustave - Branch - Hoffmann, Walter - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Gumprich, Hermann - Branch - Notes and Memoir Excerpts, 1980s-1990s? (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Gumprich/ Plaut Genealogy, 1995-1999 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Gumprich/ Rosenthal (Salomon Gumprich/ Julie Rosenthal) Branch, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Gumprich/ Rosenthal Branch - Rosenberg, Ada - Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Gumprich, Siegfried - Branch - Notes and Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Gumprich, Walter - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Gumprich, Walter and Louise - Correspondence, 1975-1990 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Gumprich, Walter and Michelle - Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      - Gumprichs of Muenster/ Westphalia (Book) - Drafts, undated, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      - Gumprichs of Muenster/ Westphalia (Book) - Ordering and Distribution, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      - Gumprichs of Muenster/ Westphalia (Book) - Publishing, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      - Gumprichs of Muenster/ Westphalia (Book) - Research Notes and Drafts, 1973-1999 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      - Hebrew Union College - Books - Research Notes, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      - Hebrew Union College Inquiry - Jews in Hessen, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 45)
      - Jacobius, Hanna (Gumprich), 1986 (Box 8, Folder 46)
      - Jacobson, Johanna Gumprich, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      - Jews in Muenster, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      - Landfield, Ruth, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      - Leeser Family Tree - Correspondence and Notes, 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      - Letters and Invitations, 1918, 1965-1995 (Box 8, Folder 51)
      - Loser, Hilde - Corespondence, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      - Mehler Family - Wolff, Benno and Gertrude, 1972-1988 (Box 8, Folder 53)
      - Muenster - Schlautman-Overmeyer, Rita - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 54)
      - Muenster Deaths 1933-1945 - Index Excerpts, 1980s? (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Photographs, 1940-1997 (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Plaut, Selma Gumprich, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Plaut, Selma Gumprich - Memorial Certificates, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - Reeves, Roma - Israel Trip, 1996-1998 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - Steinberg, Alice, 1973-1991 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Steinberg, Alice - 100th Birthday, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Steinberg, Alice - Reminiscences, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Steinberg, Michael, 1985-1996 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Stern, Rudi - Correspondence, 1981-1991 (Box 8, Folder 64)
      - Stern, Rudi - Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - Weinberg, Lotte Jaffee - Correspondence, 1979-1997 (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Weinberg, Robert - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 67)
      - Weinberg, Robert - Correspondence, 1974-1985 (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - Weissensee Cemetery - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Windmueller Branch - Family Trees, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - B) Rosenthal
      - Family Trees, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Family Trees, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Rosenthal, Alfred - Correspondence, 1974-1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Rosenthal Data, 1893-1936, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Rosenthal Data - Unsorted, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Rosenthal, Joseph - Branch - Family Trees, 1980s? (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Rosenthal, Marcus - Branch - Family Trees and Notes, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Rosenthal, Marcus - Records, 1858-1876 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Rosenthal, Philipp - Branch - Family Trees, 1990s? (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Rosenthal Porcelain, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Rosenthal Records - Detmold, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Rosenthal, Shoshona and Chanon, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Schnock, Walter - Correspondence, 1973-1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Spanier, Edward - Correspondence, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Spier Family - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Series II: Elizabeth Strauss Plaut Genealogy, 1847-1999; 3.125 linear feet.
  Divided into seven subseries by family branch:
  Subseries 1: Abraham/ Strauss
  Subseries 2: Dreifus/ Dreyfus/ Dreyfoos
  Subseries 3: Kline
  Subseries 4: Rauh/ Mack
  Subseries 5: Wertheimer
  Subseries 6: Wisebart
  Subseries 7: Wormser/ Guggenheim
  Series II holds research into the ancestors of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut, and chiefly involves material on the Guggenheim/Wormser, Abraham, Strauss, Dreyfoos, Kline, Wisebart, Wertheimer, Rauh, and Mack families. During processing, these families were seen to have the largest volume of files. The prominent volume of material on these branches of the family, along with Elizabeth Plaut's notations, served as the basis for the creation of seven subseries.
  Any information provided by Elizabeth Strauss on the original envelopes of the files has been retained in this finding aid, including the names of correspondents. Untitled files were assigned titles during processing based on format, individual, or general topic. Folders of correspondence with an individual's name that include the word "branch" indicate correspondence that appears to relate to research on this specific branch of the family tree.
  Papers in this series primarily include correspondence between Elizabeth Strauss Plaut and her relatives that mention her work on the family genealogy, as well as discussing family news. Other papers consist of family trees, notes on family genealogy, and copies of articles on family members.
  - Subseries 1: Abraham/ Strauss, 1851-1999; 0.75 linear foot.
    Alphabetical.
    Subseries 1 contains papers of the Abraham and Strauss families, and includes information on Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's mother, Therese Abraham Strauss and her grandfather, Victor Abraham. Much of this subseries consists of correspondence on family genealogy and family trees, as well as documentation and notes on branches of the family and individuals.
    Several folders in this subseries focus on the life of Therese Abraham Strauss. Among the documentation here are several versions of a memoir by Therese Strauss that describes her childhood and early years. Papers relating to the memoir include a foreword and postscript written by Elizabeth Plaut, correspondence regarding its publication by the American Jewish Historical Society, and a précis for a proposed autobiography of Therese Abraham Strauss. Other documentation on her include copies of music critiques, advertisements for her symphony appearances, and professional correspondence. There is also one folder of letters sent to Therese Strauss by her daughter Elizabeth during the early 1960s.
    - Abraham Family Trees, undated (Box OS 128)
    - Abraham, Charles Victor, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Abraham Family, 1960-1994 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Abraham Family - Australia and London, 1936, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Abraham Family - London, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Abraham Family Members - Articles and Notes, 1889-1941, 1980s? (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Abraham, Louis, undated, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - [Abraham?], Rick - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Abraham/ Strauss Data, 1851-1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Abraham, Victor, undated, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Abraham, Victor, undated, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Abraham, Victor - Branch - Correspondence and Notes, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      Abraham?, Kathleen 1966-1973
      Abraham, Walter 1973-1974, 1986
      Gryn, Hugo 1973
      May, Mr. [Unidentified] 1973
      Mitchell, Eva 1973
    - Abraham, Victor - Ethical Will - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Abraham, Victor - Rockdale Temple (Cincinnati, Ohio), 1905, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Abraham, Walter - Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Braham, Leonora, 1931, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - De Young Family - Chestnut Street Cemetery (Cincinnati), undated, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Fagin Wedding Data, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Frank, William Klee - Biography, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Heller Family Research - Correspondence and Notes, 1924, 1973-1994 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Heller, William - Independent Order of the Sons of Benjamin - Articles and Notes, undated, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, David Israel, 1957, 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Johnson Family Branch - Correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      Arnold, Mary 1986-1989
      Roche, Henry J. 1988-1990
    - King, Jeffrey - Correspondence, 1977, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Lehman, Alan - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Mendelsohn, Betty Abraham, undated, 1960-1983 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Sprinz, Julius, 1940, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Stern, Betsy Pollack - Correspondence, 1980-1993 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Strauss Correspondence - Loose, 1985, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Strauss, Elsa Lovitt, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Strauss Family Data, undated, 1921, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Strauss Family from Riedenburg - Philip Strauss Branch - Family Trees, 1980s? (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Strauss Family Members, 1903-1991 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Strauss Family Members - Data - Articles, 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 48)
      Mendelsohn, Barbara 1985-1989
      Mendelsohn, Harry 1988
      Strauss, Linda Leopold 1988
    - Strauss Family Members - Unidentified, undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Strauss Family - New York City Cemetery Records - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Strauss Family - Notes, 1990-1995 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Strauss Family - Photographs, Invitations, Song Texts, 1907-1922 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Strauss Family - Washington Cemetery (Brooklyn), 1892-1921, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Strauss, Harry A. - Will - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Strauss/ Heller Branch (William Strauss/ Pauline Heller) - Correspondence, 1973-1995 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      American Jewish Archives 1976
      Appel, Murray 1977
      Baer, Hugh and Ruth 1977, 1988
      King, Nancy A. 1977-1978
      Melzer, Joan S. 1981-1995
      Schmiedler, Kate 1979
      [Sprinz?], Bennett 1973
      Sprinz, Steve 1973-1977
      [Strauss?], Marion 1977-1979
    - Strauss/ Heller Branch [William Strauss/ Pauline Heller] - Family Trees, 1980s-1990s? (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Strauss, Raphael - Branch - Correspondence, 1972-1982 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      Block, Edna 1973
      Miller, Marian 1978-1982
      Plaut, Arthur 1972
    - Strauss, Raphael - Family Data - Notes and Family Trees, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham, 1900-1947 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham, 1962, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Correspondence - Recitals and Performances, 1894-1903 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Memoir - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Memoir - Manuscripts, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Memoir - Manuscripts - Handwritten, 1947? (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Memoir - Précis and Notes, 1981? (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Music Critiques, 1900-1905 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham - Symphony Appearance, 1900-1904, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Strauss, Therese Abraham and Victor Abraham, 1851, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Strauss, William (Bill) and Nina - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Subseries 2: Dreifus/ Dreyfus/ Dreyfoos, 1847-1997; 0.5 linear foot.
    This subseries holds papers related to the Dreyfoos family (spelled alternatively Dreifus, Dreyfus, or Dreifuss), including some of related families such as the Pappenheimers and Guggenheimers. The subseries is comprised of genealogical correspondence and family trees as well as research in the form of notes and photocopied articles.
    - Aldingen and Ludwigsburg - Notes from Dale Dreyfoos, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Alsace-Lorraine - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Arkansas Pappenheimers - Correspondence, 1977-1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Hoffheimer, Jon 1989
      LeMaster, Carolyn Gray 1985-1993
      Mack, Millard 1989
      Marcus, Jacob (American Jewish Archives) 1989